Bernard Sam Apoh

Date of birth: 05/12/1990 | **Nationality:** Ghanaian | **Gender:** Male | (+233) 0248315982 |

sb.bernardsam@gmail.com | Box AF 1030 Adenta Accra, 00233, Accra, Ghana

About me:

Versatile developer and electronic engineer with over 3 years of leveraging software engineering and implementing new technologies to maximize development efficiency. Conducting extensive market and consumer research to translate into effective web development. Acquiring and applying new technology concepts in a short period of time.

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Programming languages (JavaScript, Python and C++) | HTML CSS SASS Bootstrap | jQuery Ajax ES6 | Python Flask Intermediate Knowledge | Currently learning MongodDB ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS | Database Management System (MySQL, SQL) | Modern Responsive Design | Touch Typing | Social Media | Microsoft Office (Microsoft)

PROJECTS

Websites

https://bernardsam.netlify.app/ https://mastamind.net/questions

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/2021 - CURRENT - Accra, Ghana

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN AND BATCH PLANT OPERATOR - DBS INDUSTRIES

- Interprets electric and electronic schematics to diagnose problems.
- Tests wiring and other system parts for electrical flow and function.
- Installs electrical conduit and wiring for power, controls, and lighting.
- Collaborates with IT department with any networking issues such as printing and data access.
- Performs preventive maintenance tasks to verify the proper working condition of electrical panels and conduits.
- Sets up batch based on specifications and capabilities for admixtures.
- Calculates water to cement ratio for specific mixes.
- Quickly shuts down equipment in emergency situations following protocols.

01/2018 - CURRENT - Tema, Ghana

WEB DEVELOPER - HORIZONS SOLUTIONS

- Troubleshoots and debugs code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Develops user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Maintains quality assurance through code testing and cross-browser testing.
- Studies user requirements and implemented requirements into solutions.
- Studies basic project requirements with assigned technical lead and planned development strategies.
- Develops testing code for mobile and web-based applications.
- Uses critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.

ELECTRONIC ENGINEER INTERN - HORIZONS SOLUTIONS

- Worked on hardware design (microcontroller, sensors, circuit) for the need of client.
- Tested the individual I/O devices in smart home system.
- Developed smart home applicant system with HTML, JavaScript, CSS.
- Performed design, board layout, assembly, and testing debugging.
- Operated CNC machine for producing PCB.

05/2016 - 07/2016 - Accra, Ghana

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER INTERN - ACCRA BREWERIES LIMITED

- Completed functional analysis and root cause tests.
- Collected, organized and modeled data to coordinate reports.
- Monitored installation and operations to consistently meet rigorous customer requirements.
- Applied principles of electrical theory to advance and improve product development and efficiency.
- Troubleshoot electrical equipment problems such as electro-valves and sensors.
- Assisted in the replacing of faulty motors and installations of new motors

05/2014 - 07/2014 - Accra, Ghana

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER INTERN - ACCRA BREWERIES LIMITED

- Assisted in monitoring and controlling of plant from the control room to maintain safe efficient and continuous plant operation.
- Assisted in ensuring rapid response to alarms/emergencies to maintain service and safeguard station equipment.
- Assisted in the replacing of faulty motors and installations of new motors.
- Planning and creating and undertaking routine maintenance.
- Adhered to all applicable regulations, policies and procedures for health, safety and environmental compliance.

11/2015 - 06/2016 - Tarkwa

ELECTRONIC ENGINEER INTERN - INFITECH LABS LTD

- Delivered products to customer locations within specific timeframes.
- Used Microsoft Word and other software tools to create documents and other communications.
- A team member in the development of an optimized RF-based light bulb.
- Handled parts selection and sourcing of components for projects.

10/2017 - 03/2018 - Accra, Ghana

VOLUNTEER STAFF - CEDARS ACADEMY

- Assisted teachers to prepare teaching and presentation materials.
- Assisted headmistress in the administrative works of the school.
- Giving a hands-on experience in electronics through project buildings.
- Empowered students with computer programming fundamentals.
 Assisted students to choose their career paths.

09/2016 - 08/2017 - Accra, Ghana

CALL CENTRE AGENT – GHANA INVESTMENT FUND FOR ELECTRONIC COMMUNICATIONS (GHIFEC)

- Took customer calls and provided satisfactory answers to their query and concerns.
- Relayed customer's concern to the appropriate security and health services.
- De-escalated and calmed situations involving customers robbery attacked or idleness.
- Kept the customer's company in dangerous situations till security personnel arrived at the scene.
- Helped to train new employees and inform them about the company's customer management policies.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

08/2012 - 06/2016

BSC. ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING – University of Mines and Technology, Tarkwa, Ghana

Website https://umat.edu.gh/

10/2007 - 06/2011

WEST AFRICAN SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE - St. Augustine's College, Cape Coast, Ghana

Website https://www.auguscocapecoast.edu.gh/